Stern, Robert Papers /4231
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert Stern Papers
1975-1980
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Stern, Robert
/4231
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8056640
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Casey Westerman, May 20, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 05, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Robert Stern (May 12, 1948-April 22, 2001)
Robert Stern was a superb teacher and scholar, and an inspiration to faculty, staff, and students in the ILR School.
Bob joined the School in 1974, after earning an A.B. degree from Washington University in St. Louis in 1970, and
M.A. and Ph.D. degrees in Sociology from Vanderbilt University.
Professor Stern's research focused on problems of organizational governance and on the sources and nature of
organizational conflict.
Bob was an original member of the ILR School's Teaching Advisory Committee, and he was the committee's spark,
always looking for ways to improve his own teaching and that of others. He also was a mentor of young faculty
members, both in his own department of Organizational Behavior and in other departments within the School.
In 1997, despite mounting health problems, Bob became the Director of Graduate Studies in the ILR School. He
reasoned that if he could not do as much scholarly research as in the past, he could still serve the School in another
capacity. Bob was an excellent choice for the job: he was committed to both the professional masters program and
to the M.S./Ph.D. program, he enjoyed meeting prospective students, he was interested in the work of people in
disciplines other than his own, he was fair, and he always was sympathetic to students with academic, personal,
or financial problems.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4050: Robert Stern Canadian Postal Study Archives Data Files
Stern, Robert.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8056640
- Yearbook Listings (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newspaper and Magazine Articles (Box 1, Folder 2)
- #1 Aldrich- Organization sets (Box 1, Folder 3)
- #2 Weich- Loosely Coupled Systems (Box 1, Folder 4)
- #3 Aldrich- Visionaries&Villians- System Coupling (Box 1, Folder 5)
- #4 Stover and Brown- Compliance with Law: Utility Theory (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Regulations and Notes (Box 1, Folder 7)
- NCAA Research (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence and Research (Box 1, Folder 9)
- NCAA- Sanctions Data- Raw (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Interorg. Control Framework and History (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Notes and Rankings (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Rankings, Data Sets and Notes (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Data Sheets (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Random Notes on Control and Papers (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Regulation of College Athletics (Box 1, Folder 16)
- NCAA (Box 1, Folder 17)
- NCAA- Summary (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Articles and Papers on Women in Sports- Title IX (Box 1, Folder 19)
- The Ad-hoc Committee on Athletic Dept. Management (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Title IX intercollegiate Athletics- Investigators Manual (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Census Information- 1920, 1930, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Data/State and County Codes- 1840, 1940, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Data Printouts (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Data Printouts (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Columbia Conserve Information/Southern Cooperatives Information (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Producers Co-ops Code Book (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Data/State and County Codes (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Census Information- 1840/Data/State and County Numbers (Box 3, Folder 4)
- English Small Shopkeepers Study: Code Book/Correspondence/History/Data (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Coding Forms (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Coding Forms (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Notes and Articles (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Coding Scheme for Producers Cooperative Historical File (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Coding Scheme for Producers Cooperative Historical File (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New England w/out Div (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Coding Scheme for Producers Cooperative Historical File (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Coding Scheme for Producers Cooperative Historical File (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Coding Scheme for Producers Cooperative Historical File (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Coding Scheme for Producers Cooperative Historical File (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Articles on History/Essays on Producer Cooperatives (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Cross Reference Links (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Middle States/ Notes (Box 4, Folder 11)
- History Project: Correspondence (outgoing) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Working Indexes (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Working Indexes (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Bibliographies/ Codebook for Producers Cooperative Historical Study/Data (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Cooperatives/ Artisanship, Spring 1980- Drop, Aldrich, and Stern/Notes (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Addresses for Various State Co-ops (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Specific Articles on Unions and Co-ops (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Derek Jones' Papers (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Constitutions (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Sources (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Producers Cooperatives- General Information- Sources (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Information from States Concerning Producer Co-ops- Historical Society Responses (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Census Information- 1790-1950 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Organization Set Size and Diversity: Links Between People Processing Organizations and Their Environments (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Code List (Box 7, Folder 1)
- State and County Codes for Census- 1850, 1860, 1870 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Printouts from First Book (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Printouts from Second Book (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Half the Printouts from Book Three (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Second Half of the Printouts from Book Three (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Printouts (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Census Information- 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Census Information- 1930, 1920, 1910, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Census Information- 1890, 1880, 1870 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Census Information- 1860, 1850 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Data Printouts (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Producer Co-op Information (Box 8, Folder 7)